<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OpenSSF Glossary – Acronym</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/tags/acronym/</link><description>Recent content in Acronym on OpenSSF Glossary</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://glossary.openssf.org/tags/acronym/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>: CI/CD Pipeline (Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery)</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/ci-cd-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/ci-cd-pipeline/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A process that automates the building, testing, and deployment of software. CI/CD stands for continuous integration and continuous delivery. Continuous integration is the practice of integrating code changes as regularly as possible. Continuous delivery is a set of practices in which code changes are automatically deployed into an acceptance environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: CIA Triad</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/cia-triad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/cia-triad/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The CIA triad represents the three pillars of information security: confidentiality, integrity, and availability, as follows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Confidentiality – preserving authorized restrictions on information access and disclosure, including means for protecting personal privacy and proprietary information&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Integrity – guarding against improper information modification or destruction and ensuring information non-repudiation and authenticity&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Availability – ensuring timely and reliable access to and use of information&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="https://www.nccoe.nist.gov/publication/1800-26/VolA/index.html">https://www.nccoe.nist.gov/publication/1800-26/VolA/index.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: CISA</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/cisa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/cisa/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) of the United States government serves as the national coordinator for critical infrastructure security and resilience. The agency&amp;rsquo;s stated mission is to &amp;ldquo;lead the national effort to understand, manage, and reduce risk to our cyber and physical infrastructure.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/about">https://www.cisa.gov/about&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: Cloud Security Posture Management (CSPM)</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/cloud-security-posture-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/cloud-security-posture-management/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Cloud security posture management (CSPM) identifies and remediates risk by automating visibility, uninterrupted monitoring, threat detection, and remediation workflows to search for misconfigurations across diverse cloud environments and infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE)</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/common-vulnerabilities-exposures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/common-vulnerabilities-exposures/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A list of publicly disclosed computer security flaws. When someone refers to a CVE, they mean a security flaw assigned a CVE ID number. The mission of the CVE Program is to identify, define, and catalog publicly disclosed cyber security vulnerabilities. There is one CVE Record for each vulnerability in the catalog. The vulnerabilities are discovered then assigned and published by organizations from around the world that have partnered with the CVE Program. Partners publish CVE Records to communicate consistent descriptions of vulnerabilities. Information technology and cyber security professionals use CVE Records to ensure they are discussing the same issue, and to coordinate their efforts to prioritize and address the vulnerabilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/About/Overview">https://www.cve.org/About/Overview&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: Critical Information Infrastructure (CII)</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/critical-information-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/critical-information-infrastructure/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Critical Information Infrastructure (CII) constitutes assets (real/virtual), networks, systems, processes, information, and functions that are vital to a nation such that their incapacity or destruction would have a devastating impact on national security, the economic and social well-being of citizens. CII may comprise a number of different infrastructures with essential interdependencies and critical information flows between them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/topics/critical-infrastructure-security-and-resilience/critical-infrastructure-sectors">https://www.cisa.gov/topics/critical-infrastructure-security-and-resilience/critical-infrastructure-sectors&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: DAST</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/dast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/dast/</guid><description>
&lt;p>DAST is an acronym for Dynamic Application Security Testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is agreement that DAST executes a program (that is, it uses dynamic analysis instead of static analysis) to find vulnerabilities. However, while the term DAST is often seen in the literature, the &lt;em>meaning&lt;/em> of DAST has variation in industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By some definitions, DAST is dynamic analysis for finding vulnerabilities in (only) web applications (see VeraCode, &lt;a href="https://www.veracode.com/security/dast-test">&lt;em>DAST TEST: Benefits of a DAST test for application security&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, 2020). This makes the term DAST mostly equivalent to the use of &lt;em>web application scanners&lt;/em>. John Breeden II (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3487708/9-top-fuzzing-tools-finding-the-weirdest-application-errors.html">&lt;em>9 top fuzzing tools: Finding the weirdest application errors&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, 2019) states this and expressly differentiates DAST from fuzzing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Others definitions use the term DAST more broadly, where dynamic analysis is used to find vulnerabilities where the &amp;ldquo;tester has no [necessary] prior knowledge of the system&amp;rdquo;. Under this definition, DAST includes web application scanners, fuzzers, and other dynamic approaches that can be applied to applications. Examples include Thomas Scanlon (&lt;a href="https://insights.sei.cmu.edu/sei_blog/2018/07/10-types-of-application-security-testing-tools-when-and-how-to-use-them.html">&lt;em>10 Types of Application Security Testing Tools: When and How to Use Them&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, 2018) and Sergej Dechand (&lt;a href="https://blog.code-intelligence.com/what-is-fast">&lt;em>What is FAST?&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, 2020) includes web application scanners and fuzzers under “DAST”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-204C.pdf">NIST Special Publication 800-204C&lt;/a>
attempts to split the difference, defining DAST as analyzing
&amp;ldquo;applications in their dynamic, running state during testing or
operational phases. They simulate attacks against an application
(typically web-enabled applications, services, and APIs), analyze
the application’s reactions, and determine whether it is vulnerable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-204C.pdf">https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-204C.pdf&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: MITRE</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/mitre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/mitre/</guid><description>
&lt;p>MITRE is a not-for-profit company in the United States founded in 1958 to serve as objective advisers in systems engineering to government agencies, both military and civilian. MITRE operates federally funded research and development centers (FFRDCs) including the National Cybersecurity FFRDC. The NCF is sponsored by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) and supports NIST&amp;rsquo;s Cybersecurity Center of Excellence, a collaborative hub for government, industry, and academia to build practical solutions to cybersecurity challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="https://www.mitre.org/">https://www.mitre.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: NIST</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/nist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/nist/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) was founded in 1901 and is part of the U.S. Department of Commerce. NIST&amp;rsquo;s stated mission is &amp;ldquo;to promote U.S. innovation and industrial competitiveness by advancing measurement science, standards, and technology in ways that enhance economic security and improve our quality of life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/about-nist">https://www.nist.gov/about-nist&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>