<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OpenSSF Glossary – Defense</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/tags/defense/</link><description>Recent content in Defense on OpenSSF Glossary</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://glossary.openssf.org/tags/defense/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>: Blue Team</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/blue-team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/blue-team/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A group of security professionals responsible for defending an enterprise&amp;rsquo;s use of information systems by maintaining its security posture against a group of mock attackers (i.e., the Red Team). Typically the Blue Team and its supporters must defend against real or simulated attacks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/glossary/term/blue_team">https://csrc.nist.gov/glossary/term/blue_team&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: Branch Protection</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/branch-protection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/branch-protection/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A feature that helps secure code by enforcing rules on git branches. The rules define whether collaborators can delete or force push to the branch and set requirements for any pushes to the branch, such as passing status checks or a linear commit history.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: CI/CD Pipeline Security</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/ci-cd-pipeline-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/ci-cd-pipeline-security/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The process of integrating security controls into the CI/CD pipeline to protect code and software delivery.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: Cloud Security Posture Management (CSPM)</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/cloud-security-posture-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/cloud-security-posture-management/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Cloud security posture management (CSPM) identifies and remediates risk by automating visibility, uninterrupted monitoring, threat detection, and remediation workflows to search for misconfigurations across diverse cloud environments and infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: Content Security Policy (CSP)</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/content-security-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/content-security-policy/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Content Security Policy (CSP) is a feature that helps to prevent or minimize the risk of certain types of security threats. It consists of a series of instructions from a website to a browser, which instruct the browser to place restrictions on the things that the code comprising the site is allowed to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary use case for CSP is to control which resources, in particular JavaScript resources, a document is allowed to load. This is mainly used as a defense against cross-site scripting (XSS) attacks, in which an attacker is able to inject malicious code into the victim&amp;rsquo;s site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A CSP can have other purposes as well, including defending against clickjacking and helping to ensure that a site&amp;rsquo;s pages will be loaded over HTTPS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CSP">https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CSP&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>