<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OpenSSF Glossary – Organization</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/tags/organization/</link><description>Recent content in Organization on OpenSSF Glossary</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://glossary.openssf.org/tags/organization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>: CISA</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/cisa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/cisa/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) of the United States government serves as the national coordinator for critical infrastructure security and resilience. The agency&amp;rsquo;s stated mission is to &amp;ldquo;lead the national effort to understand, manage, and reduce risk to our cyber and physical infrastructure.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/about">https://www.cisa.gov/about&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: MITRE</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/mitre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/mitre/</guid><description>
&lt;p>MITRE is a not-for-profit company in the United States founded in 1958 to serve as objective advisers in systems engineering to government agencies, both military and civilian. MITRE operates federally funded research and development centers (FFRDCs) including the National Cybersecurity FFRDC. The NCF is sponsored by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) and supports NIST&amp;rsquo;s Cybersecurity Center of Excellence, a collaborative hub for government, industry, and academia to build practical solutions to cybersecurity challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="https://www.mitre.org/">https://www.mitre.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>: NIST</title><link>https://glossary.openssf.org/nist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.openssf.org/nist/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) was founded in 1901 and is part of the U.S. Department of Commerce. NIST&amp;rsquo;s stated mission is &amp;ldquo;to promote U.S. innovation and industrial competitiveness by advancing measurement science, standards, and technology in ways that enhance economic security and improve our quality of life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/about-nist">https://www.nist.gov/about-nist&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>